The prophecy is clear.
She is the child that shall
bring about the end of destiny.
Lyra!
A city in the sky,
a myriad of worlds
of which the Magisterium
controls only one.
They labelled
Dust as original sin
to keep us on our knees.
Lord Asriel needs to die.
You're quite terrified of him,
aren't you?
Lyra, it's an alethiometer.
It tells you the truth.
ALETHIOMETER WHIRS
It worked.
Roger is my best friend.
My only friend.
This is Mrs Coulter.
We have an opportunity
to understand Dust.
Why am I so important to her?
She's your mother, Lyra.
We have to find out
what she's doing.
Once we've ironed out the teething
problems... Mother!
..this will change the world.
Lee Scoresby.
I can fight and I can fly.
We need you. And the bear.
Iorek Byrnison!
You are going to need
all the help you can get.
Call yourself a father?
I think that's rather the point.
I've never called myself a father.
No!
In war, there are casualties.
Roger!
This is a war.
Lyra, look.
The city in the sky!
GRUNTS
I'm Will Parry. Lyra Silvertongue.
You're not from here, are you?
From this world? Me neither.
I lost my best friend, and I think
about him every single day.
My dad left me and my mum
to go off to the Arctic.
He's dead.
Mr Jopari, I've come here
humbly to ask for your help.
The Subtle Knife.
It could slice between worlds.
You have this knife, do you?
I want to find
the person who does.
Sorry, you are?
Lyra Silvertongue. Mary Malone.
We study something called
dark matter. Must be Dust.
My war was never
just with the Magisterium.
There's a far more dangerous
power out there.
Our child is in this world.
My place is with her.
Dad.
You must go to Lord Asriel
and tell him that
you have the only weapon
that can destroy the Authority.
GUNSHOT
What are you?
Angels.
Save the girl...and the boy.
If Asriel has angels on his side,
he can do anything.
ANGELS: We stand with you,
Asriel Belacqua.
Then let us prepare for war.
I've discovered
the girl has another name.
She is my daughter.
She is my daughter!
What is the child's name?
Eve.
She must be protected.
Sacrifice...
..whatever is necessary.
We're out of danger.
I'm taking you somewhere
entirely safe.
For many millennia,
the Authority has ruled
in the Kingdom of Heaven...
..with absolute control.
He named himself the Creator,
the Father, the Almighty.
He is none of those,
but just an angel like ourselves.
And he rules
with a dark angel by his side.
We who fought for truth
were cast out of the Kingdom.
Since then, we have
lived between the worlds,
watching and waiting
for vengeance.
A spark of hope is alive
among humankind.
A bold leader is rallying warriors.
He may be mortal,
but his ambitions
transcend his kind.
A serpent has been summoned.
A new Eve emerges.
The time for a new rebellion...
..is coming.
THUNDER RUMBLES
Lyra!
Lyra...
I'm looking for a girl.
Medium height, dark hair,
brown eyes.
Her name's Lyra.
She has a daemon called Pan.
She's missing.
Help me.
Tell me where she is.
WIND WHISTLES
ECHOING: Pan?
Pan?
ECHOING: Lyra!
Roger!
Is that you?!
I need you! Help me!
Where are you?
Roger!
FOOTSTEPS APPROACH
GROWLING
Lyra.
SNARLING
RUSTLING
LOW RUMBLING
Come on. Come on.
For goodness' sake.
Craft may not be ready
for this.
Well, that is on
the pair of us, is it not?
GRUNTS
Clear your mind.
CRAFT GROANS
BREATHES DEEPLY, SLOWLY
MECHANICAL CLICKING
We've lost the rear oscillator.
GRUNTS
CLICKING CONTINUES
And...brace!
GRUNTS SOFTLY
Please.
Let us go.
Here, drink this.
LYRA WHIMPERS
If you don't drink your medicine,
how will you get better, darling?
Hmm?
Here.
FAINT WHOOSHING
GASPS
KNIFE RINGS
WHOOSHING
ECHOING: Don't be afraid.
How...how did you...?
We're not going to hurt you.
What are you?
Bene elim.
Angels, in your language.
We come to you in human form.
Angels?
We just want to talk.
Stop following me.
SLICING
Aesahaettr.
It's real.
GROANS
I think the craft
is pretty much done for.
And how will we get back
to the Republic?
We'll be able to figure
something out.
See anything?
It looks like the path is clear.
Commander, let's go get our man.
FLUTTERING OF WINGS
Follow my lead.
Hey. Hey!
Clear.
Are we secure?
Clear. Clear.
All clear.
Ogunwe?
Which one of you
is Commander Ogunwe?
I am.
Who are you
and your little friends?
I am Lord Asriel Belacqua.
I intend to march
upon the Kingdom of Heaven
and I should very
much like you to join me.
I've heard stories about you.
You have just
made war with the Temple.
I'll let you fight that one.
Listen to what he has to say.
My friends and I,
we are not from your world.
We have little interest
in your temple.
We came here for you.
Join with me in my fight
against the Authority.
Look, I know that
we stand for the same thing.
I know the number you command.
I want your army,
but I need your leadership.
Come with me.
Be a part of the final victory.
You can come with me.
Welcome to Geneva,
Cardinal MacPhail.
Father President, please.
Father President.
Tell me of this arrest.
We recovered this material
from the site.
It was recited before
an audience, many inebriated,
and followed by feverish discussion
and a grotesque exchange of ideas.
Poems.
Father Jerome.
What do you think should be done?
The author must be imprisoned
for heresy.
Father Heyst.
There were dozens more like it
hidden throughout the building.
All attendees imprisoned,
as well as anyone found in
possession of the author's work.
Mm-hm.
Father...?
Gomez.
Father Gomez.
If you were in my position,
what would you do?
Physical atonement.
In public.
For those charged with possession,
I'd choose perhaps the whip.
For the author, something which
leaves a little more...
..lasting damage.
Fear is a gift.
It allows people to learn.
He will make examples of us.
Baruch, we do not have time.
We need that knife.
I told you to stop following me.
How can you cut through worlds?
We are made of
Dust and can pass through
invisible spaces in the air,
gateways into other worlds.
We can see them, but you cannot.
Balthamos and I have been
searching for Aesahaettr,
for you,
because there is a great war coming.
All conscious beings
are engaged in a battle already,
though not all of us know it.
The enemy's power is
growing stronger every minute,
and you have the weapon
that will enable us to win.
You must come
with us to Lord Asriel.
He is gathering an army...
I know who he is.
Someone told me about him.
About all of it.
The war.
How I'm supposed to fight
alongside Asriel, with this.
I can't go with you.
I'm sorry.
I'm looking for my friend Lyra.
Asriel's daughter.
Not that he cares, but...
..she's lost and she needs my help.
You don't understand - that knife is
more important than you can imagine.
No, YOU don't understand.
Lyra's the most
important thing to me right now.
I'm going to find her.
You will come with us now!
Or what?
I'm sorry about your friend.
I can see she means a lot to you.
Do you know what happened to her?
We were attacked.
She was taken.
By who? I don't know.
I went ahead without her.
I thought she would be safe.
But when I came back,
she was gone.
Whatever Asriel wants,
he can wait.
I'm sorry.
You do realise we're just going to
keep following you
until you change your mind? Well,
you can keep following me because...
You've managed to find me
every time I've cut through.
How? The knife.
It attracts Dust.
We have senses that humans do not.
Help me find her.
If you can find me,
you can find Lyra.
Take me to her.
Then I'll come with you to Asriel.
We do not have time.
It will not take them long, Baruch.
They will find us.
So we will be quick.
Balthamos, we don't have a choice.
This was Lyra's.
She says it's powered
the same way as the knife.
Maybe you can use it to find her.
It's powered by Dust?
Oh, yes.
We will need a little time,
but we will find her,
whatever world she is in.
BUZZER
ECHOING: Lyra! Up here!
Wait, I'm coming!
Roger, what is this place?
I hate it!
Roger!
I'm scared!
Roger...
Come on.
Machi!
Father!
OGUNWE CHUCKLES
God, I missed you. Oh, my sweet.
Look at you.
CHEERFUL CHATTER
Daddy has work to do.
I'll be right back.
SNIFFS
You have a beautiful little girl.
How long since you last saw her?
Ten months and 16 days.
I had no hope of leaving that cell
until you and your
cat came to recruit me.
What?
I'm trying to decide
if you're a madman...
..or a genius.
Well, I rather hoped
the two could coexist.
So, Lord Asriel,
tell me who your war is really
against and what you want from me.
My fight is with
the Authority himself...
You said that before,
but it's impossible.
Humankind cannot
stand against its Creator.
Well, he forces us to kneel at
his feet, but he is not the Creator.
It's all a lie.
He's an angel.
An angel?
Nothing more.
And how do you know all this?
Even if it were true.
Some millennia ago,
another angel discovered
the Authority's secret.
Now that angel, Xaphania,
sits on my council.
Ogunwe,
I am gathering the greatest
from every world,
from even the heavens above,
but I want you
to help me wage my war.
I should be flattered.
Well, I have come
rather a long way,
so, yes, you should.
Lord Asriel...
..I cannot help you.
Machi is my youngest daughter.
But I have another.
The Temple have been targeting
our children for a while now.
But in recent years,
they began taking them away...
..for training.
Aria...
..is the property of the Temple.
To her...
..I do not exist.
There is only the Authority.
And the girl I knew...
..she's gone.
But she's still my child.
I understand what you offer,
but I have my
own battles here to fight,
and an obligation
to save as many sons...
..and daughters as I can.
May I?
Please?
I've seen this before.
Her daemon has been severed.
She is not demonic!
I did not say she was, forgive me.
Please, if you'll
allow me to explain.
Stelmaria?
Stelmaria and I are one.
She is my daemon.
My soul, if you use that word.
Aria's daemon resided within.
The link that
binds us to our daemon
is immensely powerful,
but when it is severed,
well...
..very little remains.
They are taking our souls, Ogunwe,
and with them our humanity,
to make us easier to control.
To make us this.
DISTANT HUMMING
Drones!
Get Machi underground!
Everyone inside now!
Hold your fire.
They're trying to draw us out.
CLICKING
You sent for me, Father President.
Come in, Father Gomez.
I have come to Geneva
on a matter of great significance.
Fra Pavel's alethiometer
has informed me of a prophecy,
which, if true,
and I believe it is,
risks plunging us into a darkness
the like of which
the world has not experienced.
There is a girl wandering the earth
at this very moment,
and she is Eve,
the mother of us all.
And, of course, of all sin.
The instrument says that if this
child is tempted by the serpent,
she will likely fall. And if she
does fall, then sin...
..and Dust will triumph.
This cannot happen.
So we stop her.
Where is she?
Unfortunately, we are at the mercy
of the instrument and its user.
Fra Pavel's work is unbearably slow.
When he does locate the child...
..we will send
troops to retrieve her.
And I would like you,
Father Gomez, to lead them.
It would be an honour.
I could perhaps
drop in on Fra Pavel,
see if I can speed him up a little.
Please.
BREATHES SHAKILY
FIRE CRACKLES
All these men after you.
I tell you, it'll never change.
There are forces out there that you
can't begin to understand.
I wish you wouldn't
look at me like that.
Would you rather
I didn't keep her safe?
You're keeping her prisoner.
Let us go.
'Fraid I can't.
GROWLS
RUSTLING
You've found her?
You were right.
She is in the
world of the daemons.
Where?
She's with a woman who is
holding her against her will
in a house carved into the rocks.
It's on a remote
island in the German Ocean.
You'll need passage on a ship.
But Lyra's not harmed?
No, just asleep, and dreaming.
What can you
tell me about the woman?
Her daemon is a golden monkey.
Her mother.
Her mother? Lyra's mother
is the worst possible person
she could be with.
Balthamos will take you to her.
I must go to Asriel and
tell him about you and Aesahaettr.
Are you sure this is safe?
Go straight to Lyra, and we will be
together again before long.
I do not remember
agreeing to accompany the boy.
Stay close to him.
As soon as the
children are reunited,
you will both come
to me in Asriel's republic?
MOUTHS
WIND GUSTS
Father President MacPhail sent me.
Where is the girl?
I am close, Father, I assure you.
SQUEAKS
I see this task
has weighed heavily on you.
The pressure.
Such great responsibility.
It must muddle the mind terribly.
It is this final part
of the reading, its meaning...
SQUEAKS SOFTLY
FRA PAVEL SIGHS
..eludes me.
SQUEAKING
I just need a little more time.
We can only do that of which
we are capable.
Father President has advised
that if the coordinates
are not forthcoming,
then perhaps the time has come to...
..re-educate you. No.
No.
I will find her.
I promise.
I have no doubt that you will.
WHISPERS: Lyra, wake up, please.
Look.
We can get away.
GASPS
PURRS SOFTLY
PANTS
GOLDEN MONKEY SCREECHES
Lyra?
She's coming.
You're not going to make it.
We have to try.
Hide here.
Maybe someone will see us.
PANTS
Lyra?
Lyra!
Where is she?
I can't see.
Lyra?
LAUGHING
Lyra, where are you?
You never cease to amaze me.
WHISPERS: Please...
Mm.
Hmm.
I do understand
why you're doing this.
It must be strange,
being here like this...
..with me.
I haven't brought you
here to keep you jailed.
I've done it to keep you safe.
Lyra, darling...
..there are people coming for you.
Dangerous people.
You're so brave.
So courageous.
I know you won't believe me,
but I...
..I am doing this for you.
Come on, darling, let me help.
I will never be safe with you.
WHIMPERS
I'm sorry.
Commander,
they're heading for the mines.
They will miss us by four miles.
Good.
We'll stay covered until sundown.
Putting up a good fight, Commander,
but the battle
you're engaged in is too small.
Even if you win this
fight against the Temple,
the Authority will send
more servants in their place
to put you back on your knees.
They are in every world.
I've seen it.
You keep talking of other worlds
as if you expect me to believe them.
I do not lie.
This is but one world among many.
In every single one of them,
the same thing.
Children - mutilated.
Science, learning - criminalised.
And whole civilisations
cowering under the sky.
I was like you once.
In my world, the Temple, they are
called the Magisterium,
and I have wasted
most of my life fighting them,
until I discovered
that they were but one
arm of the Authority's might,
and that beast has countless arms.
The only fight worth risking
your children's lives for
lies elsewhere.
My republic
down here in the good earth
against his kingdom
up there in the sky.
It is the only way to win.
We cut off the head of the beast
and the rest will crumble.
No!
No.
What you ask me
to believe is too great.
It's a lot to take in.
So let me show you.
Show me? That way you can decide
for yourself.
Let me take you to another world.
SOFT GRUNTING
Please.
Just let me be.
I'll think of something.
I just thought
he'd be here by now.
Do you know how she reads it?
No.
Readers of those instruments
have normally studied many years.
Even then,
they can only understand
with the help of books.
She wasn't making it up.
Perhaps
she's a very skilled inventor.
She can read it.
It told her things
she could have never known,
like where my father was.
It's part of her,
just like the knife's part of me.
SIGHS
That's the port we're looking for.
Now we just need a ship.
COMMOTION
I am King Iorek Byrnison!
GROWLING, SHOUTING
GROWLS
You trapped one of my bears!
Release her now!
GROWLING
I think I know that bear.
I can talk to him. What?
FIERCE GROWLING
It's Lyra's friend.
ROARS
Where is she?!
SCREAMS
Stop!
Come on!
ROARS
Stop!
Stop.
Get out of my way, child.
You have to stop.
There are innocent people here.
They have taken one of my bears!
What do you want?
I want to fight you.
In single combat.
If I win,
you leave these people alone.
If I lose, do whatever
you want with them and me.
You wish to fight me?
It would be shameful to fight you.
You are as weak
as an oyster out of its shell.
Let's make it a fair fight, then.
You have all that armour.
I have none.
Give me a piece. Anything you want.
We'll be better matched then,
won't we?
Do you know
what you are doing, boy?
Sky iron, am I right?
Impenetrable, I heard.
That's surprising.
I guess I'll have to fight you
without armour, after all.
I cannot fight that.
That knife is too strange.
You win, boy.
Free that bear now.
You heard the boy! Do it!
TOWNSPEOPLE: Do it!
What is your name, child?
Will Parry.
So, Will Parry,
you're looking for Lyra?
She's with her mother,
being held against her will.
Then we must go to her.
Father President.
I visited Fra Pavel.
Several times. Ah.
I helped him to...
..focus his mind...a little.
He has since divined that
the child is with her mother.
The mother.
With this information,
I am confident
I can locate the girl myself.
And I will need to
use methods that aren't...
..officially sanctioned.
You must do
whatever you need to do.
The second you have
their position, go to them,
get the child, get the mother
and bring them directly to me.
Marisa Coulter is evil.
She is persuasive.
Do not trust her.
Father,
I've done pre-emptive penance
every day of my adult life.
I will do...whatever...
..is required to get them here.
Your dedication to the
Authority will not go unappreciated.
CHITTERING
Asriel.
I do hope you're
not walking me to my death.
Death is a lie.
You're wrong.
Death is real.
I've seen it.
More than my fair share at battle.
Commander, somehow the
Authority has managed to pervert
the natural order of Dust.
I don't know how,
but when I find out, believe me,
death is going to die.
I believe I've heard enough.
You'll see.
Stelmaria, on my mark,
I want you to bite down.
You ready?
In three, two, one.
PIERCING BOOM
LAUGHS
LAUGHS HEARTILY
See?
Welcome to the
Republic of Heaven, Commander.
I'd gather my people if I were you.
The real war is
coming and we must win it.