Cancel the Twenty-one Demands!
Give back Qingdao! We swear on our lives!
Democracy.
Science.
Wing Chun Martial Arts School
Mr. Ip Master Chan
Please come in OK
Finish the lesson for me
Yes, Master. How are you, Mr. Ip?
Girl's stuff, no substance
Watch your mouth, Man!
Master Ng Mui created this Wing Chun fist style,
the secret is the control of power with flexibility
It's my honour and pleasure to see
this fine class of disciples you have, Master Chan
Mr. Ip, I've heard that you're travelling between
Hong Kong and Foshan
Business must be doing well, then
Oh, before I forget, I must pay you the rent
No hurry, no hurry. We're good friends!
You rent Mulberry Garden to me at such a low
rent;
I have not yet found an opportunity
Seriously, it won't be hard to pay back the favor,
if you wish
Man!
Yes, Dad!
This is my youngest son, lp Man,
my own flesh and blood
Tin Chi! Dad!
This is my adopted son who has been with us for
a year now,
Tin Chi
The purpose of my trip here today is to get them
a superb master
A master?
Yes! They both have a passion for Kung Fu
Please accept this tea to show my commitment,
Master
Please accept the tea, Master
As members of our school,
you two must observe the guiding principles
Martial arts learning - genuine and authentic;
behavior - proper and discrete;
judgement - objective and rational
Understood, Master
Didn't you say that you love Kung Fu, Man?
Many other disciples will keep you company.
I have to go to Hong Kong on business
Dad, take good care of yourself!
Make sure you look after your little brother, Tin
Chi
Dad, I will, I promise
Dad!
Time to take the medicine, Master
Leave it there!
Remember! All hand movements are clearly
directed by the intention in mind;
if your intention is justified, you're on the right
track
Master, the medicine is getting cold
You have shown improvement
Remember! The noble mind commands authentic
style- movements,
which allow stability when you defend, and
invincibility when you attack
The essence of Wing Chun is to follow one's
shadow, not his hand.
Focus on what you feel rather than what you see.
Understand?
Yes, Master
Maintain world peace;
establish the Greater East Asia Co-prosperity
Sphere
You are the hope of our Empire,
Japan's future rests with you
Dad...
Tin Chi, wake up! Are you having a bad dream?
What... were... you saying?
Are you hungry? In fact, I'm hungry, too
There's nothing to eat at all
Look! Two huge rats coming out to find
something to eat!
You'll be dead if the master finds out
Not him, it's me
It's... me... not him
Hush!
Since you gave me a toffee,
I'll help you out!
This is for you
Why do fried double-sticks only come in pairs?
How nice if there were three pieces
Drink this one, Master
This bowl is freshly made
You're so busy
The medicine won't be as effective if it's reheated
Chung So, you are dedicated and dutiful,
I'll be happy to see you inherit this school
Man is gifted in martial arts
Give him the best after I'm gone.
Yes!
Go watch them!
Master! Master!
Stay away, stay clear.
Have a smooth voyage, Master! Give us your
blessing
The sun is setting, clear of obstruction and ill luck
Raise the casket
Lower the casket
This is my promise and my oath to Master Wah
Shun:
I, Chung So, will exert all energy, with all my
might,
to make authentic Wing Chun prosper for as long
as I live
1, 2, 3, 4
palms up, strike, withdraw, reach out, strike
1, 2, 3, 4, palms up, strike
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
Withdraw
All right! That's it for the day.
Go home
Tin Chi, you were quite good today
Take a rest, Man!
Hey! Listen to Brother Chung So. Let's eat!
Mei Wai, let me help you set the table
Good!
Rest! Dinner's ready
All right!
Spend the Lantern Festival with sweets
Enjoy sweet dumplings together
Tin Chi, how lucky we are!
A leather-silhouette puppet show has opened
across the street
Bringing us such good business
It's not luck, this was carefully planned
You're wonderful!
Lp Man, this was specially saved for you
I've had six bowls already, I'm so full
Why are you still eating, then?
Go take a walk to help your digestion
Tin Chi, business is quite good;
I want to take time off to look around
Fine!
Lantern Festival, see if I'll have some... romantic
luck
Alright, I'll stay,
you fellows have a good time
Alright Alright
Come on, let's go!
Wait for me!
Mei Wai, you can't just go
Who will cook the dumplings?
I'll go with you when they return
No, thanks
Look! Foreigners can play Chinese chess
Chinese can play foreigners' games, too!
If foreigners are capable of learning Chinese
culture,
we can take up Western culture, too
Let's go over there! Let's go
See you later
You surely know what good stuff is
This is the biggest invention of this century: The
gramophone
It can contain your most beautiful voice
Amazing! Even voices can be captured now
This is an English folk song
The story is that King Henry Vlll wrote it
for a girl who rejected his love.
Really? That's amazing! The girl had character
Oh my God! How can I sell this?
You scratched my record
How am I going to sell it?
I didn't mean it... Well... I'll pay you for it
This is very expensive. Do you have the money?
All right, boss, I'll buy it from you
When the record is scratched, the song won't
play smoothly
Didn't I say I'd pay for it? Is this enough?
May I know your name, please, Miss?
I'll pay you back
Don't worry about it
Thank you
Sister!
We don't have a gramophone at home. What did
you buy the record for?
I wasn't buying a record, I was buying a feeling
You hit my head with that thing. Pay!
Sorry, Sir! I don't have the money
I don't care
You've got to pay me 50 silver dollars
Where will I find 50 silver dollars?
No money, eh?
Sister!
What are you getting at? Tricking people?
What? Get back! Get up
I clearly saw what happened
The bamboo spinner fell on the ground, it didn't
hit you at all
How dare you meddle with me!
I'm warning you,
if you don't stop right now, I'll alert the police
You need a beating!
No, she doesn't
You bums do!
Strike!
To hell with you!
Sister!
Hold it!
Please spare my life!
I'll never do this again, never!
Go!
Thanks for such great help. It's much appreciated
Your act of chivalry is greatly admired
Could you leave your name?
Don't worry about it
Miss, he's lp Man, and I'm Siu Shan
I'm Yiu Choi
We are from the Wing Chun School
You may call us the Three Wing Chun
Musketeers
Don't forget your record, sis
Why bother with other people's business. Are
you hurt?
No, let's go!
Move!
Can I help you?
I'm looking for lp Man lp Man?
He's out
If you have something for him, you can leave it
with me
No! I was told to
deliver this letter in person
It's up to you. You can wait if you want
You can also feed the huge mosquitoes
Huge mosquitoes? Wait!
All right!
You must give this letter to lp Man. Thank you!
Thank you
Uncle lp! Mei Wai!
Please go in, lp Man's home
Dad! Dad!
What have you brought back?
It's Sis' new toy
Be careful! It's very heavy!
What's taking him so long to reply?
Hasn't he?
Honestly, did you deliver it in person?
I did!
Are you sure? Absolutely!
Keep this medicine with you,
it's good for headache, fever, diarrhea, everything
I appreciate it
You'll be on your own studying in Hong Kong,
Man!
Take good care of yourself Yes!
So long, Brother Chung So
Remember not to waste any time in Hong Kong
Neglect neither your studies nor your martial arts
training;
do not forget our Master's advice
Don't get involved in fights, don't think you're
better than others
Martial arts learning - genuine and authentic;
behavior - proper and discrete; judgement -
objective and rational.
Don't worry!
Good morning Good morning
Good Morning, Reverend
Good morning, class
Practice more at home, understand?
Is lp Man at home, please?
He's gone to Hong Kong. May I know who's
asking for him, please?
It's nothing important. Thank you.
Good morning, Brother Chung So
Good morning Let's eat fried sticks
These fried sticks look very interesting
You are all big eaters, double sticks aren't
enough to feed you
So I made them triple
Let's eat!
Why are you people so unhygienic?
You want to know why? Come on!
Do you know now?
Let me help you
Don't bother!
There you are! How nice!
Chairman Lee Godfather
Thanks for looking after me, Mei Wai
Here's a present for you
How beautiful! Thank you
Tin Chi, you have given tremendous help
ever since you joined the Jing Wu Athletic
Association
Don't mention it
Anyway, I have a present for you, too
Thank you, Chairman Lee
These were selected from
my jade collection
They seem like a pair
Definitely, a pair, like you two
I've never seen Chinese pigs playing hockey
before
It's so funny!
Hey, you! Mind your language.
My language? It's none of your business
I heard you say Chinese pigs
Oh, no, no! I'm sorry, I don't mean Chinese pigs
I mean... Sick Man of East Asia!
Come on, then!
I'll give you three minutes
No, two minutes
No, one minute
Good!
Just 45 seconds!
Take a seat
Relax
It's OK
Your Kung Fu is formidable
We call it Wing Chun
What's your friend's name? He's wonderful
His name is...
Good morning, lp Man! Morning
Master lp, morning Say Good morning to him!
Morning! Have I met them before?
Good morning, lp Man
Not this one, I'm sure
Boss!
I'm not the boss here, I'm the manager
How can I help?
I need some medicine for a friend
What else would you buy in a drug store, kid
Which is better to treat bruises, powder or
ointment?
What? He's injured? What happened?
A fight? What else?
Who beat him?
I did
I thought he was your friend
That's how we became friends
Why did you beat him?
Boss, why don't you...
Why don't you bring him here?
Here to receive treatment?
Treatment? Bring him here so I can beat him, too
Make sure he won't call us 'Chinese pigs' again
Where did you learn about that?
From your friends
You and your name are known to everybody on
this street now, lp Man
You're popular, kid. So, you're studying Wing
Chun?
Authentic Wing Chun. The name was inherited
from the school taught by Master Leung Jan from
Foshan
So you must be one of Chin's (Nickname of Chan
Wah Shun) disciples
Correct! Authentic my foot.
So much so that you made me believe you
learned directly from Master Ng Mui
How long have you studied it?
Finished the lower body strength training yet?
What about 'targeted finger'?
You're in Wing Chun, too, boss?
First, I told you I'm not the boss;
I'm the manager here
Second, I am practicing Wing Chun,
but don't know if it's considered authentic
Do you want to try it out?
Next time
I might be too busy next time
If you want to try me, try me now
Better not, if there is any injury...
Are you looking down on old folks like me?
Come on!
Mr Manager!
Hasn' t your master taught you that when
practicing with the others,
you reserve only the strength applied, not the
skill?
What, despise me?
I mean business then
Are you alright, kid?
I'm fine
Well, again!
Watch my medicine!
Be careful with the Three-Prick Wine
Wait! You call this Wing Chun?
Whatever comes from my fist is Wing Chun
They are not Wing Chun
My Master said Wing Chun strategic movements
30% from the legs, and focus on attacking an
opponent's lower body
Your master wasn't wrong
The traditional focus is on the use of the hands
But that doesn't mean it forbids changes
Changes allow more flexibility
Movements can be adapted in multiple ways,
such as leg movements in a form of wrestling,
and they all work
May I know your name, please?
I'm Leung Bik from Foshan
People call me Sir Bik
Master Leung Jan was my father
You're my senior!
So is my Wing Chun authentic?
You're funny
Come back the day after tomorrow, kid
Come here the day after tomorrow?
Don't you want lessons?
Of course I do
But I can't afford to pay you
Did I ask you to pay?
Customs inspection. Open the crates, officers!
Hold it!
Inspection is not authorized. The medicine was
purchased from
the Japanese Chamber of Commerce by the
British Embassy
Mr. Kitano said you can't open this as it was
purchased from
the Japanese Chamber of Commerce by the
British Embassy
I don't understand English
How dare a low-ranking customs officer
display public contempt for the Japanese
business bureau
Should any damage be incurred, who will be held
responsible?
How dare a low-ranking customs officer like you
display public contempt for the Japanese
business bureau
Should any damage be incurred, who will be held
responsible?
If smuggling is going on, who will be held
responsible, then?
Officers, open the crates!
Mr. Kitano said you can't open this
Stop!
What do you think you're doing?
Do you know who this gentleman is?
Do you know how much Mr. Kitano donates to
Foshan every year?
My apologies! Mr. Kitano
You may take the goods
What're you standing here for? Clear the way!
Of course I welcome donations
But if they are from the Japanese, I will definitely
decline
Why did you make such a comment, Chairman?
Japan's evil intentions became apparent
after the Russo-Japanese War, they annexed our
territory...
and built the Manchurian Railway,
aiming at economic invasion
Look at what they did in the North-East,
their ambitions are obvious
I think I understand how the Chairman feels
But the thing is, the Japanese Chamber of
Commerce in Foshan
did not participate in the North-Eastern affair
Mr. Kitano came here only to do business,
not much different from other foreign investors
So I think we should treat his donation
the same way as others
I don't believe the Japanese
would make a donation without a personal
agenda
Well... after he's done business for so long in
Foshan,
this could probably be his gesture of retuning a
favor
Don't be suspicious
You're in business, too, Tin Chi
Why don't you tell us what you think,
as a newcomer?
I tend to agree with what Chairman Lee
suggested
After all, our Association is on very sound
financial ground,
and is not urgently in need of donations
Tin Chi, I'm going back to the school
See you later
Try to talk Chairman Lee
out of being so stubborn, Tin Chi
Mr. Mayor, we are all educated people
Why should we allow the uneducated
to upset us?
You are right
Goodbye Take care
Bye
The improved version of Wing Chun is the good
use of
'distant fist, near elbow, close wrestling,
incorporating long and short distance movements'
Wing Chun wrestling uses the reverse joint
principle;
no need to hold on to your opponent
Your Master concentrated on
the long stretch and low kick
My improved version of Wing Chun
incorporates the short stretch and high kick
Wing Chun should not be described as
'authentic' or 'non-authentic' anymore
To me, Wing Chun is one big family,
there is no distinction between you, me, and him
Goodbye, Man lp
Our surname goes first, Reverend
lp Man, all the best
Same to you, goodbye Goodbye
Let's go
Bye, lp Man! Bye!
Goodbye! Bye!
Thank you Thank you
You should have told me you were coming back,
lp Man
Mei Wai lp Man's back, everybody!
You brought back so many things
Only this one is mine,
the rest are presents for you all
We know lp Man is good to us!
Let's go This is for you
For me?
How am I supposed to finish all these toffees
Don't eat them all, some are for my brother to sell
Man! Tin Chi's back!
Brother! There you are!
Yes! Long time no see.
You're still stout. Keeping up with martial arts
practice?
Do you want to try me? Sure!
Give it to me
One point for Man
Great! Another point for you, Man!
What style is this?
Wing Chun!
The high kick doesn't exist in Wing Chun,
where did you pick that up?
Try me more first OK
Good! One point for Tin Chi
Excellent! Good!
Don't tell me this is Wing Chun, Man?
This is fantastic. Show me, lp Man
It's wonderful! Teach me, too
Me, too Me first!
One at a time
Mei Wai
Mei Wai, watch out!
Is this necessary, Man?
I'm all right. Take it easy next time
Take a rest, Mei Wai
Let's learn it together
To reward your enthusiasm. Come on!
Alright?
Amazing!
This focuses on the reverse joint principle
It's a different approach like Japanese Judo,
there's no need to hold on to your opponent
It's amazing! I want to learn, too
Me, too Count me in
Brother Chung So
Let me help you
Such a fat chicken, let me take care of it
Remember what Master Chan said to you, Man?
Time to go home
Let's go!
I ask you
Whose style is authentic,
our Master Chan's or Leung Bik's?
Leung Bik?
Brother Chung So, Mr Leung and our Master are
from the same school;
his style shouldn't be considered deviant from
authenticity
Also, Leung Bik is Grand Master Leung Jan's
son;
he practiced with him since he was a child
But he never got along with the Grand Master,
nor with his brothers. Leung Bik is conceited
Perhaps... he held different views
Despite a difference in views,
he shouldn't have created tension in the family
I remember after the Grand Master passed away,
Bik's brother immendiately put up a wall...
to partition the two families;
you can see how badly he was received by the
others
He's a bit strange,
but we can't assume that his art is not competent
People often thought that Wing Chun seldom
uses wrestling moves
But he believes that by applying the targeted
finger style
or darting hand movements, opponents can be
overpowered
I've tried it and it's very effective
Comparing Bik's with the tradional moves, his
allow more flexibility
Let me tell you, the Wing Chun Leung Bik has
learned...
only accounts for a fraction of his father's
Most of his movements are made up
How can one improve without deconstructing the
old?
You are greedy to aspire for more before
you can manage the basic Wing Chun principles
You'll end up gaining nothing
I'm fed up. Enjoy your meal
Don't get upset, Brother Chung So
Man just got back, give him a chance!
Fine! He has his chance now
Show me the sort of deviance you've picked up
Get up, up!
Brother Chung So! Brother Chung So!
Brother Chung So! Stay away!
What happened to the things Leung Bik taught
you?
Brother Chung So! Man!
Lp Man should be feeling sorry by now
Brother Chung So, that's enough!
Was it Wing Chun that he just demonstrated?
Does our school have high kick like that?
Or elbow as low as his?
Now, I demand you all go on your knees in front
of our master and vow that...
you will never again learn anything that deviates
from our school tradition
They have nothing to do with this, Brother Chung
So
It was me who wanted to try things out
They never said they wanted to learn it from me
I'm the only one who deserves punishment for
this
I have taught you all I know, Man
Thank you, Master!
Stop calling me master
Why?
Your master is Chan Wah Shun;
you have to show due respect
When I was young, I was too emotional
to try to think from another's perspective
And my family was too conservative
to accept my innovative ideas,
thus causing a lot of misunderstanding and
friction
In order to aviod conflict,
I decided to leave Foshan
Master, lp Man is gifted,
but he's such an ungrateful brat
Do you think I should expel him?
Please give me instruction, Master
If you think I should,
please show 'the head' when I toss the coin
Master, lp Man is young and restless;
he's doomed to make some mistakes
And... perhaps it's not entirely his fault
I might not be competent enough as an instructor
Why don't we do it three times to decide on the
result?
Thanks, Master
Thanks, Master, thanks a great deal
You are...
We heard that your Association has a reputation
for the vision of
promoting martial arts on the grounds of
abolishing segregation of schools
So we're here to join the Association
I'm glad that you share the same vision
How may I address you?
Before we enroll, I'd like to see
whether the Association is qualified to teach us
I don't quite understand what you mean
You need to show a sample when you sell goods
So we'd like to check out how competent the
masters are first
This is not how our Association operates
Don't make things difficult
All right, then. If you don't want to demonstate
we'll be happy to take over
You just came to create trouble
Hold it!
Wait a minute!
Father
Chairman Kitano,
what do you want from us?
Not much, I only want to say hello
I don't think so, it's more like picking a fight
This is a place to learn martial arts;
I don't see why not!
Chairman Lee, allow me
Good! Good fight!
Stop! What are you doing?
Good! Good show!
Sorry that my daughter isn't as capable
Valour is better demonstrated by the young!
Come and have a snack, lp Man
Yours Triple fried sticks
Yes! My creation
Three-sided. How can one person finish it?
It's for all three of us. We each have one
You two have the crispy sides,
the middle part is not as crunchy
The triple stick is what you wanted when you
were a kid
I didn't say that
You really don't remember, eh?
It seemed that I had a sense of humour when I
was a kid
Too bad you have none left
I won't eat any more Mei Wai...
What have I said wrong?
No! Let's eat
Oh yes! I forgot to congratulate you
On what?
On your successful career in business, young
and hopeful
What's more, Chairman Lee will recommend you
for Vice Chairman
a bright future lies ahead of you
Stop teasing me. I owe this to Brother Chung
So's leadership
What's your plan after graduation?
I won't keep it from you, but don't laugh at me,
alright?
I'd like to start a martial arts school
to promote Wing Chun
What a wonderful idea! If you start in Foshan,
I'll come up with the capital for you
Not just in Foshan, I want it all over the world
I want to show the world how wonderful Wing
Chun is
The world? Great!
Congratulations to you, Guru of Wing Chun,
who will breed numerous splendid students
Thank you!
Also, when you become popular,
let's make a film
to promote Wing Chun to the whole world
You'll contribute the capital, and me, the hard
work
Good! What about profit?
Let's say thirty seventy Fifty fifty!
You forty me sixty. Definite!
The congee is getting cold. Eat!
Done deal! Let's eat first!
Sis!
What?
The mayor's son is here. He wants to ask you out
to a film
And Dad has agreed on your behalf
Is that right? Yes!
Did he say what film?
Do you really want to go? What about lp Man?
What about your freedom of romanatic love
Freedom of romantic love?
I've waited so long, but have yet to find my love
Perhaps lp Man and I are not connected
Do you really think so?
Or else how could I have done so much but to no
avail
What else can I do about it?
Look! A new film is on
I don't think you're a fan of horrors
Let's go have a drink
No! I want to see the film
I'll go get the ticket, then
This way please!
Here's your ticket, have a seat.
Ip Man?
Miss Justice?
Aren't you the daughter of the Deputy Major?
How are you?
Hello! Watching this film, too?
Yes, what a small world!
Miss Cheung was looking for you, Man
Really? Anything important?
Let's wait until the end of the film
You're not even afraid of thugs
I thought you're the fearless kind
Of course I'm fearless
Don't touch me! What's happening now?
Now Dracula is moving towards the female lead
and about to bite her
Is the biting over? He's still biting
Alright, you may open your eyes now
Are you sure?
Yes!
I'm Dracula So am I
Scared the wits out of me. Excuse me
Please allow me to take you home, Miss Cheung
Don't worry about it, Mr. Cho, bye!
Come on... Miss Cheung, when will we...
Three yams, please!
Thanks for taking me to the film, thank you very
much.
See you Bye!
Buying yams?
Where did you pick up your Englsih, Miss
Cheung?
I learned it myself
My brother took Englsih lessons in Hong Kong,
too
Perhaps you two can get together
and practise speaking it
Where are we heading now?
Tomorrow will be our Master's birthday, we'll go
buy a chicken
OK Let's leave, Mei Wai
We don't speak English, neither do you!
Let's go
Didn't you say you had something to ask me?
No need now
You're amusing,
yet I have a question to ask you
Please do
I've not got your name
Didn't you address me as Miss Justice?
I like it
You're not going to tell me
My name is Cheung Wing Shing
The feeling of thinking of a person,
whose name is not known,
is like listening to a song
without knowing the title
Or you know the person's name,
but not what he's thinking about
The feeling is like listening to a song,
when the title is familiar but not the tune
One, two, three, four
Is it hurting you?
It's not nice to me. Beat it up
Watch me!
Like this, one, two
So slow, speed it up,
come on, come on
Don't laugh, laughing drains energy
Look at you, being around this log all day long
You've grown to be loglike,
hopelessly inarticulate
How can I be more expressive, then?
You can exercise your thoughts, for instance...
Think of something you like
or somebody you want to be with
Well, I'll stick your name here, then,
Cheung... Wing... Shing
So you want to beat me up every day?
No, no, no! I just want to be with you
lp Man! Go and help prepare dinner
I'm taking Wing Shing out for dinner
Come over here, Wing Shing, I have something
to tell you
Go clean the study Yes, Sir!
What do you want to tell me, Dad?
You've made a major mistake, Wing Shing
What major mistake?
The worst I could think of was giving the Mayor's
son the cold shoulder
You shouldn't have gone out with that martial arts
guy, lp Man
If you loathe martial arts guys so much,
why do you support the Jing Wu Athletic
Association, then?
I support them because my job requires it
Our freidnship is not based on a job
I'm not a hypocrite like you
Me a hypocrite? I'm your dad
why won't you listen to me?
I'm just worried that you make friends who are a
bad influence
and bring disgrace on the family
Unless you don't care much about our family,
go back to your room and reflect
For you Thank you
I'm sure it'll bring a lot of sweet dreams
I'm afraid that we might have to stop seeing each
other
What happened?
I'm here to see Deputy Mayor Cheung
Please come in!
Please take a seat, Sir
OK, it's done
I hope to see you soon, Mr. Cheung
The pleasure was all mine
See you soon
By the way, where can I purchase bone china?
He wants to find out where he can purchase
some Chinese bones
Chinese bones?
The British simply adore bone china
The British have developed a taste for Chinese
bones
I think he can get a better price from the
slaughter house
Go to the Killing Animal House to buy some
Killing Animal?
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Kill, kill, kill
In that place they kill chickens, kill cows,
kill pigs, kill ducks, kill geese...
Good. Thank you OK!
Sir!
The British would like to buy bone China
He wants bone china!
Just kidding
Mr. Cheung says he can take you to buy very
good china bone
Just kidding
Thanks for doing the favor for me
Goodbye Goodbye
Your English is not bad, young man
Your name? Lp Man
So you're lp Man, here for Wing Shing?
I'm here to pay a special visit to Mr. Deputy
Mayor
Pay me a visit?
Something's happening, sis!
What are you fussing about?
Lp Man's here lp Man's here?
He came to see Dad. I don't know what they're
up to. Come and see
Let me help you! No, thanks!
Let's go to a movie tonight
What about the others?
Siu Shan and Yiu Choi don't like dramas
What about lp Man?
Lp Man... has company
Let me think about it
Don't think for too long. The movie will be off soon
When do you want to go, then?
Actually, I've already got two tickets
Too bad I couldn't get toffee,
only some chocolates
Good day, Master Ng. This is a present from Mr.
Chan
Thank you, Yiu Choi! Yes!
Take the presents to the main hall
This way, please! Thank you!
Look at these paper cuts, Man
Thanks for your trouble Thank you!
Lay it out properly
Hey, move the left lantern more to the left
All right!
Move the right lantern more to the right
Finished?
Is my writing all right?
Tin Chi! Lp Man!
Put these couplets on the front door
Alright!
I'll get the rice paste, be back soon
Hurry!
Mr. Ip Tin Chi
Can I help you?
The Kitanos asked me
to deliver a gift on your big day
Happy wedding day!
I really want to know how you feel now
Thank you all! Cheers!
Hope you have beautiful kids
I appreciate it Congratulations!
Please take a seat!
Mr. Ip, please sit down! Thanks
What a great evening!
Tin Chi's got himself a wife and I've got a
daughter
I'm very happy, too. To me, Mei Wai is like half a
while Tin Chi is half a son
Now half a daughter is marrying half a son;
half a son is marrying half a daughter
The two halves together form a perfect couple
Don't forget that Tin Chi is my whole son
I'm most thrilled to see him
marrying your half daughter
You'll have another happy occasion very soon
I believe it'll be lp Man's turn soon
Keep up the good work, Man!
Tin Chi, have a wonderful wedding night!
Thanks! Congratulations on your promotion
to the Deputy Chairmanship, too. Cheers!
Thank you! Why don't we fill up the glasses?
Bottoms up! Bottoms up!
Bottoms up! Tin Chi, work hard!
I know, Dad. Cheers!
To my woman
To my man
Cheers again! Great!
Come on!
Master!
He was very happy and is a bit tipsy
Stay here tonight, Man
Go to sleep, go!
Yes, Sir!
Watch your step Man
Let's fill our glasses again
It's getting late, President Lee
What do you mean by late?
The night is still young
Tin Chi said your martial arts skill is superb
Come on! Show me your skills
Next time!
Why next time? Let's do it tonight
President Lee, seriously, it's getting late!
Let's not start late, then
President Lee!
Sir!
We don't need you here. Retire to your room
Let's try again President Lee!
Let's go! Yes, Sir
Sit tight, off we go!
Master Ng, Master lp,
where's Tin Chi? Isn't he coming?
It was his wedding night last night
I'll tell him later
Let's go in first
Master This way
I can't imagine the honorable and respected
President ended up with such a tragic death
We must locate the murderer,
the President cannot die in vain
Show me in
Have you reported to the police?
Not yet We'd better report it first
Right away Got it!
Where's my brother? In his room
lp Tin Chi!
Lp Tin Chi!
Lp Tin Chi, come with me
What's wrong? You stay here
You come with me right now; I have to talk to you
What's the matter?
People should have qualms of conscience
What're you getting at?
Didn't Lee Man Ho treat you like his son?
Why did you do that?
What've I done?
Are you out of your mind?
Stop acting innocent!
Strangle me if you have the balls
I have no clue what you're talking about
You strangled President Lee, only you used left
hand
Lee is dead?
I won't let him die in vain!
Let go of him, Man!
What are you two doing? Why start a fight?
Your Godfather was killed
Look this man in the eyes. He is the killer
All because he was strangled with the left hand,
you're accusing me of murder
I'm not the only one in Foshan who's learned the
strangling move
You taught me this move
You know how to strangle with your left hand,
too.
The Japanese want to get rid of their opponents
You must be the one who helped them
Tell me, why did the Japanese send gifts to your
wedding?
I do business with many foreigners
It's no surprise that the Japanese would send me
presents
Swear that you have nothing to do with President
Lee's murder
All right! I, lp Tin Chi swear...
Tin Chi, the police are here
lp Man, have you reported to the police?
Mr. Ip Tin Chi,
we are here to take Mr. Ip Man to the police
station
Why are you taking my brother away?
He's suspected of President Lee's murder
Lee's servant witnessed a fight
and heated argument between lp Man and Lee
last night
The President was quite drunk
and my brother just escorted him home
No need to start a fight with President Lee
after taking him home, right?
Arrest him
You're not taking lp Man away
There must be some understanding here My
brother doesn't kill
Mr. Ip, please stop your wife from obstructing our
course of action
I'll go with them
I fear not as I'm innocent
Go!
Lp Tin Chi, remember you swore an oath
Inspector, if you don't have enough evidence to
press charges
you have to release him
Deputy Mayor, lp Man has been charged with
felony
We need more time to investigate
lp Man is innocent, you can't lock him up.
Miss Cheung, we go by evidence;
we don't bring charges against innocent citizens
There are witnesses in this case
If he's innocent,
why won't he try to defend himself?
You keep saying lp Man is innocent;
do you have evidence, Miss Cheung?
Unless you can prove his innocence, stop making
these empty claims
lp Tin Chi has been elected
President of the Jing Wu Athletic Association
Good! Congratulations!
Congratulations! Thank you!
Mr. Kitano will donate $300,000
to the Association
And will send his students here to exchange
knowledge.
Any objections?
Lee Man Ho... killers in ambush
You can leave now!
How come?
Let's get out of here first
Come on!
At 10:30 pm, the night of the murder,
lp Man came to my place
We stayed up and chatted
He was drunk and so spent the night in my room
Miss Cheung, are you telling the truth?
Were you really with lp Man on the night of the
murder?
Your testimony is critical to the case
If you're making things up,
you could be arrested
I swear the truth in my capacity as the Deputy
Mayor's daughter
However, I can't simply take your alibi
and believe that lp Man is innocent
I need more supporting evidence
More supporting evidence?
Is my daughter's chastity not enough
to prove his innocence?
I guess I need the Provincial Governor
to come and do justice
Dad, don't be too upset
I had no alternative but to make up such a lie
I'm so sorry
You sacrificed your reputation
to rescue him;
just to rescue a Kung Fu guy!
You must marry my sister as soon as you can!
Dad, don't get mad! Wing Shing!
Sorry! I'm not worth it
Worth it or not is only for me to decide
I don't want you to marry me because of this
Wing Shing!
That's not what I mean, I want you to marry me
I'll take you as my wife with an official ceremony
and a grand wedding.
Your father need not worry
Mei Wai! Mei Wai!
Mei Wai, why are you doing this?
Did you kill my Godfather, Tin Chi?
Do you work for the Japanese?
Did you betray your own people for money, or for
power?
It's not as simple as you think
It's hard to explain
Mei Wai, please don't leave me!
Listen to me
I beg you. Please listen!
What other lies do you want to tell me?
You can't die, you'll be a mother soon
But you've killed, you should give yourself in
It won't work! It won't work!
Listen!
We should go somewhere we belong
Where's the letter?
Who came?
Tell me, who came?
No... Nobody
Tell me who was here?
Brother Chung So... he came to see me just now
I've caused my brother enough damage,
I don't want to involve Brother Chung So
Where are you heading?
I've done so much for your career advancement
Dad even made lp Man the culprit for your crime
And you back out because of this lowly woman!
I've done what you told me. What more do you
want from me?
Kill Ng Chung So; he's aware that you're working
for us
For you, and for us,
whoever gets in the way should be eliminated
I don't want to kill any more!
This is not an option!
Tin Chi! Don't hurt her!
Tin Chi!
I gave you my word on the honor of a samurai:
You'll be free to leave after this mission
Don't say that you haven't been given a second
chance!
How can I overcome him?
If you can't do this alone, we'll form a brother and
sister team
Tin Chi, come out!
Tin Chi, come out quick!
We don't spare traitors in the Wing Chun Martial
Arts School
He's no longer your senior
Get him out here, now!
Tin Chi! Tin Chi!
I beg your forgiveness, Master
I've failed as a teacher and a leader
Yiu Choi! Yiu Choi!
Master!
Lp Tin Chi, you traitor!
That's no way to treat your fellow disciples
Watch out, Man! I will!
Kill him!
Clear the way!
I beat you up, not in revenge for being framed
But to defend Lee Man Ho,
the Master, and Dad's reputation
Why did you turn traitor
when you were so loved and respected by us?
I'm not a traitor!
I'm a Japanese sergeant, Tanaka Eiketsu
I left my parents when I was twelve
to become a spy in China
I miss my country,
I want to go home
I couldn't even see my mother
when she died
I have yet to be able to pay my respects at her
grave
It might not be a bad idea to die now,
so everything can be ended
I'm a soldier, which leaves me no choice
I'm relieved now
as I've finally carried out my mission
I don't need to hurt the people I love any more
It's been a pleasure to be adopted by the lp
family
and be your brother
I have no regrets,
as Mei Wai has been my wife
Where's Mei Wai now?
The essence of Wing Chun is to follow one's
shadow, not his hand.
Focus on what you feel rather than what you see
Where's Tin Chi?
I feel guilty; I wasn't able to keep his son
Captain, these crates have just arrived
They are all Kitano's
Open them for inspection!
Where am I? Who are you?
I want to go home
There's one over here, too!
Over here, too! Help him out
Any water? Give them some!
Will do!
Easy, get him out!
Dad, a beggar is unconscious outside
Don't be afraid! Leave!
Give them some water!
At the critical moment,
he arrived in a hurry with a long rod in hand,
beating the hell out of the Japanese with
the authentic Wing Chun 'half-past six' rod style
However, his rod was slashed into two halves
by your Uncle Tin Chi's Japanese sword
Yet Tin Chi didn't let go,
he pressed even harder...
by attacking lp Man with Karate and Judo
How did my Dad react?
He was very alert;
he immediately used the two half rods
like a pair of wing-shaped swords,
and brandished them frantically,
at times mixing in some unknown styles,
styles difficult to identify, to beat his opponent
These mixed movements, regardless of their
authenticity,
were not only powerful enough to win,
but also good enough to save my life
From then on, I stopped believing that martial
arts schools
should be segregated to maintain their own
authentic styles
My eyes were opened and saw a broader horizon
I don't understand how Uncle Tin Chi picked up
Japanese Kung Fu
Yeah! Why? Why?
As a matter of fact, your Uncle Tin Chi...
Why stop practicing? Dad!
Go and do more training and practice. Hurry!
Hurry!
Let's go and practice!
Telling stories again, Brother Chung So?
You've gone over them thousands of times
The thing is, every time it's a new story to them
You're right! Children should know about their
past
Pay full attention when you practice. You are not
allowed to eat before you're done
Dinner's ready, Jun! Stop the training
Come and eat, everybody!
Dad says I have to practise well before I can eat
What's more important? Martial Arts or food?
Food! Dad!
All right! Take a good rest
Practise more after you eat
Eat!