Cancel the Twenty-one Demands!
Give back Qingdao! We swear on our lives!
Democracy.
Science.
Wing Chun Martial Arts School
Mr. Ip Master Chan
Please come in OK
Finish the lesson for me
Yes, Master. How are you, Mr. Ip?
Girl's stuff, no substance
Watch your mouth, Man!
Master Ng Mui created this Wing Chun fist style,
the secret is the control of power with flexibility
It's my honour and pleasure to see
this fine class of disciples you have, Master Chan
Mr. Ip, I've heard that you're travelling between
Hong Kong and Foshan
Business must be doing well, then
Oh, before I forget, I must pay you the rent
No hurry, no hurry. We're good friends!
You rent Mulberry Garden to me at such a low
rent;
I have not yet found an opportunity
Seriously, it won't be hard to pay back the favor,
if you wish
Man!
Yes, Dad!
This is my youngest son, lp Man,
my own flesh and blood
Tin Chi! Dad!
This is my adopted son who has been with us for
a year now,
Tin Chi
The purpose of my trip here today is to get them
a superb master
A master?
Yes! They both have a passion for Kung Fu
Please accept this tea to show my commitment,
Master
Please accept the tea, Master
As members of our school,
you two must observe the guiding principles
Martial arts learning - genuine and authentic;
behavior - proper and discrete;
judgement - objective and rational
Understood, Master
Didn't you say that you love Kung Fu, Man?
Many other disciples will keep you company.
I have to go to Hong Kong on business
Dad, take good care of yourself!
Make sure you look after your little brother, Tin
Chi
Dad, I will, I promise
Dad!
Time to take the medicine, Master
Leave it there!
Remember! All hand movements are clearly
directed by the intention in mind;
if your intention is justified, you're on the right
track
Master, the medicine is getting cold
You have shown improvement
Remember! The noble mind commands authentic
style- movements,
which allow stability when you defend, and
invincibility when you attack
The essence of Wing Chun is to follow one's
shadow, not his hand.
Focus on what you feel rather than what you see.
Understand?
Yes, Master
Maintain world peace;
establish the Greater East Asia Co-prosperity
Sphere
You are the hope of our Empire,
Japan's future rests with you
Dad...
Tin Chi, wake up! Are you having a bad dream?
What... were... you saying?
Are you hungry? In fact, I'm hungry, too
There's nothing to eat at all
Look! Two huge rats coming out to find
something to eat!
You'll be dead if the master finds out
Not him, it's me
It's... me... not him
Hush!
Since you gave me a toffee,
I'll help you out!
This is for you
Why do fried double-sticks only come in pairs?
How nice if there were three pieces
Drink this one, Master
This bowl is freshly made
You're so busy
The medicine won't be as effective if it's reheated
Chung So, you are dedicated and dutiful,
I'll be happy to see you inherit this school
Man is gifted in martial arts
Give him the best after I'm gone.
Yes!
Go watch them!
Master! Master!
Stay away, stay clear.
Have a smooth voyage, Master! Give us your
blessing
The sun is setting, clear of obstruction and ill luck
Raise the casket
Lower the casket
This is my promise and my oath to Master Wah
Shun:
I, Chung So, will exert all energy, with all my
might,
to make authentic Wing Chun prosper for as long
as I live
1, 2, 3, 4
palms up, strike, withdraw, reach out, strike
1, 2, 3, 4, palms up, strike
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
Withdraw
All right! That's it for the day.
Go home
Tin Chi, you were quite good today
Take a rest, Man!
Hey! Listen to Brother Chung So. Let's eat!
Mei Wai, let me help you set the table
Good!
Rest! Dinner's ready
All right!
Spend the Lantern Festival with sweets
Enjoy sweet dumplings together
Tin Chi, how lucky we are!
A leather-silhouette puppet show has opened
across the street
Bringing us such good business
It's not luck, this was carefully planned
You're wonderful!
Lp Man, this was specially saved for you
I've had six bowls already, I'm so full
Why are you still eating, then?
Go take a walk to help your digestion
Tin Chi, business is quite good;
I want to take time off to look around
Fine!
Lantern Festival, see if I'll have some... romantic
luck
Alright, I'll stay,
you fellows have a good time
Alright Alright
Come on, let's go!
Wait for me!
Mei Wai, you can't just go
Who will cook the dumplings?
I'll go with you when they return
No, thanks
Look! Foreigners can play Chinese chess
Chinese can play foreigners' games, too!
If foreigners are capable of learning Chinese
culture,
we can take up Western culture, too
Let's go over there! Let's go
See you later
You surely know what good stuff is
This is the biggest invention of this century: The
gramophone
It can contain your most beautiful voice
Amazing! Even voices can be captured now
This is an English folk song
The story is that King Henry Vlll wrote it
for a girl who rejected his love.
Really? That's amazing! The girl had character
Oh my God! How can I sell this?
You scratched my record